In text classification, it's often useful to
在文本分类任务中
include multiple features in your final classification model.
通常有必要在最终分类模型中包含多个特征
Containment is just one measure of text similarity and in this project,
包含系数只是衡量文本相似性的一种方式
you'll also be expected to calculate the longest common subsequence or LCS,
在此项目中 你需要计算原文和答案之间的
between a source and answer text.
最长公共子序列 (LCS)
Given two texts and answer A and a source S,
给定两段文本：答案 A 和原文 S
your goal is to find the value for the longest common subsequence of words.
你的任务是计算字词的最长公共子序列
This is the longest sequence of words that appear left to right in both texts.
即在两段文本中都出现的从左到右最长字词序列
It's important to note that the words don't have to be exactly continuous,
注意 字词不需要完全连续
just in left to right order.
只需从左到右即可
Consider these sentences: A,
假设有两个句子A：
machine learning is all about finding patterns in data and forming predictions,
“machine learning is all about finding patterns in data and forming predictions.”
and S, deep learning uses neural networks to find patterns in data.
S：“deep learning uses neural networks to find patterns in data.”
To find the LCS,
为了计算LCS
we can go along word by word in each sentence.
我们可以逐个字词地查看每个句子
The first words, machine and deep, are different.
第一个字词“machine”和“deep”不一样
Then learning is a match,
然后“learning”一样
then the texts diverge again.
然后字词又不一样了
So we continue moving left to right along both texts until we see the next common words.
继续从左到右地查看这两句话 直到下个公共字词
In this case, the words patterns and data.
即字词“patterns in data”
That's the end of our source text and so we can stop
这时候已经到了原文的末尾 所以可以停止比较了
here and say that the LCS is four words total.
LCS 共 4 个字词
There's one more normalization step,
还有一个归一化步骤
which is to divide this value by the length of the answer text,
除以答案的长度
which has 12 words in it.
答案有 12 个字词
So we get our final value four over 12 or about 0.333.
最终值为 4/12 约等于 0.333
You could approach this problem recursively,
你可以递归地解决此问题
keeping track of your location in each text and counting up when you find a common word.
记录在每个文本里的位置 并在找到公共字词后加一
But a recursive approach especially for longer texts,
但是对于很长的文本来说
can be very computationally intensive.
递归方法很消耗计算资源
Instead, I recommend a dynamic programming approach,
建议采用动态规划法
which I'll go over it next.
接下来我将介绍该方法